[{"id": "5ffb68455dad637d903c8841", "question": "Which country, other than Switzerland, uses the Swiss franc?", "answer": "Liechtenstein", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b87b", "question": "Sinologists study which country?", "answer": "China", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8fd", "question": "What does the \"lithosphere\" refer to?", "answer": "The Earth's crust", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339507", "question": "Who provides the voice for Abe Sapien in the 2004 movie \"Hellboy\"?", "answer": "David Hyde Pierce", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59d1850d3b17032616b590fb", "question": "What 14th century poem contains the earliest reference to Robin Hood?", "answer": "Piers Plowman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b8cc2f94b094db9158309d", "question": "Who was the first person to receive an \"Honorary Award\" at the Academy Awards?", "answer": "Charlie Chaplin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc9", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Archie Goodwin?", "answer": "Nero Wolfe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefa4e36ce05a3942286eb8", "question": "In the film \"Ghostbusters,\" what is the occupation of Louis Tully?", "answer": "Accountant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b29d", "question": "What US president loved Fresca so much he had a soda tap installed for the Oval Office?", "answer": "Lyndon Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b3589ac5db0d66a186cb54d", "question": "Until 1989, what European country was the world\u2019s second largest exporter of bottled wine?", "answer": "Bulgaria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be5c", "question": "Oldest son Al was the first ringmaster of what famous circus?", "answer": "Ringling Brothers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd81dced0de9af39e9d4693", "question": "What state elected a former pro wrestler as its governor?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b88", "question": "What city's opera house does \"The Phantom of the Opera\" prowl?", "answer": "Paris'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4f1", "question": "What do you get by mixing ginger ale with grenadine and a cherry?", "answer": "A Shirley Temple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a8e", "question": "Who created the character Conan the Barbarian?", "answer": "Robert E. Howard", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133928a", "question": "Which legendary Knight of the Round Table does not appear in the movie \"Monty Python and the Holy Grail\"?", "answer": "Sir Kay", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a330", "question": "What year did Belle and Sebastian originally release the album \"Tigermilk\"?", "answer": "1996", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b51c", "question": "What is Whisky distilled from?", "answer": "Fermented grain mash", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392d2", "question": "What was Murray Langston better known as to the public?", "answer": "The Unknown Comic", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b987", "question": "In which year was the wearing of seat belts made compulsory in the UK?", "answer": "1983", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5feccceaec223966ae8f88a7", "question": "\"American Hustle\" is a fictionalized retelling of what famous sting operation?", "answer": "ABSCAM operation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c23", "question": "Who is the author of the Discworld series?", "answer": "Terry Pratchett", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60078bab0eee65b76b9f266b", "question": "For what is Matthew Webb famous?", "answer": "He was the first man to swim the English Channel.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c481", "question": "What is a group of feral horses called?", "answer": "A band", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b820", "question": "What flavors make up Neopolitan ice cream?", "answer": "Vanilla, chocolate and strawberry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133907f", "question": "Who wrote a book about John Harrison, entitled \"Longitude\"?", "answer": "Dava Sobel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133986d", "question": "In Disney's \"Cinderella\", who gives her a new gown and carriage for the ball?", "answer": "Her fairy godmother", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339842", "question": "Who directed the 1986 film, \"The Color of Money\"?", "answer": "Martin Scorsese", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a378", "question": "What is the capital of Finland?", "answer": "Helsinki", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a70e", "question": "What city in Ohio is known as the \"rubber capital of the US\"?", "answer": "Akron", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad9d", "question": "In what city did Rosa Parks refuse to give up her seat for a white passenger?", "answer": "Montgomery, Alabama", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339405", "question": "Who narrated the 2007 movie \"Enchanted\"?", "answer": "Julie Andrews", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3a8fc73aa70ea0b70adf", "question": "What is the oldest city in the world?", "answer": "Damascus (The capital of Syria has evidence of continuous habitation dating back at least 11,000 years)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0af", "question": "What does an anthrophage practice?", "answer": "Cannibalism", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be44", "question": "What is the only fruit to be ever banned from airplanes?", "answer": "Durian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59029feccad1ec93f27df766", "question": "What country does the cappuccino originate from?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e0", "question": "Who wrote the first three books of the \"Millennium\" novel series?", "answer": "Stieg Larsson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d57", "question": "Under which pseudonym did J. K. Rowling publish \"The Cuckoo's Calling\" in 2013?", "answer": "Robert Galbraith", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600b86681d8c1817608d53e4", "question": "What does the \"E\" stand for in Chuck E. Cheese?", "answer": "Entertainment (Restaurant founder, Nolan Bushnell, happens to be the founder of Atari.)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefbf0b6ce05a3942286efa", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Material Girl\"?", "answer": "Madonna", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f3", "question": "Who directed the 1997 movie \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Luc Besson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3f28c73aa70ea0b70afd", "question": "Mount Godwin Austen, located in the Karakoram mountain range, is better known as what?", "answer": "K2", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338920", "question": "What spice is the most essential and valuable commodity in the \"Dune\" universe?", "answer": "Melange", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133942f", "question": "Who directed the 1989 movie \"Dead Poets Society\"?", "answer": "Peter Weir", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e95a47ccba3ffe45786e2", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Rigoletto\"?", "answer": "Giuseppe Verdi", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a38f", "question": "What is the nothernmost provincial capital?", "answer": "Edmonton", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2f9", "question": "What does IQ stand for?", "answer": "Intelligence Quotient", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c964", "question": "Osteoporosis primarily affects what?", "answer": "Bones", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015ffb5fe83fe1f2a824c4f", "question": "The term \"bonfire\" originated from which two Halloween related words?", "answer": "Bone and fire -- Bonfire is associated with ancient Celts where the bones of animals were burnt in order to fend off bad spirits.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2fd", "question": "What toe is the foot reflexology pressure point for the head?", "answer": "The big one", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb0d", "question": "What is the fear of fog known as?", "answer": "Homichlophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad03", "question": "What archaeological site is known as the Lost City of the Incas?", "answer": "Machu Picchu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6018bc96d96d05b23b281658", "question": "At which hospital did the first heart transplant take place?", "answer": "Groote Schuur Hospital, Cape Town, South Africa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ab99adb21a8909e5c332d25", "question": "What is the Kelvin scale used to measure?", "answer": "Temperature", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76f5deec85e375820b2e8", "question": "Where is the world\u2019s largest jazz festival?", "answer": "Montreal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5921fe71a4edfd43a087adce", "question": "What does a ventriloquist typically hold on their lap?", "answer": "A puppet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ae", "question": "Who received a patent for the first electric razor in 1930?", "answer": "Jacob Schick", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7bb", "question": "In miles, approximately, how much Atlantic coastline does the state of New Hampshire have?", "answer": "18", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b17", "question": "What was the first name of Julia Roberts' character in the 2001 movie \"Ocean's Eleven\"?", "answer": "Tess", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dd7", "question": "What film introduced the fraternity Lambda Lambda Lambda?", "answer": "Revenge of the Nerds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65f131f3c0ead6880d634", "question": "In ancient Greece, throwing an apple at someone was a declaration of what?", "answer": "Love", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b3731c1c3f17ccc40c8e2a", "question": "In \"The Wizard of Oz\", what was the lion in search of?", "answer": "Courage", "category": "art"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397e1", "question": "Which main character dies in the 2014 movie \"The Amazing Spider-Man 2\"?", "answer": "Gwen Stacy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e93a7b2d6f11f394a3b2d57", "question": "In the manga series \"Bleach\", what is the name of Ichigo's zanpakuto?", "answer": "Zangetsu", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dc0", "question": "What double-word song title was a hit single by Paula Abdul?", "answer": "Rush Rush", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdb4", "question": "Each Pac-Man maze features 240 regular dots and how many larger \"power pellets\"?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c367", "question": "What element did Pierre and Marie Curie discover in 1898?", "answer": "Radium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba3b", "question": "Who first broke the gender barrier in NASCAR racing in 1949?", "answer": "Sara Christian", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5989adbccb8751d53e7d7611", "question": "Which Roman Emperor received the title \"Gothicus Maximus\" because of his campaign against the Goths and the Heruli?", "answer": "Tacitus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c0", "question": "From 1948 to 1950, the Fender Telecaster was known by what alternate name?", "answer": "Broadcaster", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a1e1d75b5a031299b74573b", "question": "The Okapi is native to which African country?", "answer": "Congo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133913b", "question": "What year marked the appearance of Doc Savage?", "answer": "1933", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca72", "question": "What is measured in fathoms?", "answer": "Depth of water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b36ebf1c3f17ccc40c8e0a", "question": "Which of Mark Wahlberg's brothers appears in the film \"The Sixth Sense\"?", "answer": "Donnie Wahlberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ade1", "question": "What year did the Han Dynasty come into power?", "answer": "206 BC", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339380", "question": "In the movie \"Interview with the Vampire\", what gift does Lestat give to Claudia every year?", "answer": "A doll", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd81cc8d0de9af39e9d4688", "question": "As of 2020, who was the only president to be awarded the Purple Heart?", "answer": "John F Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdfbb7a003d27d341092bc6", "question": "Where is the busiest airport in South America?", "answer": "S\u00e3o Paulo, Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba5a", "question": "Where did Chicago Bears standout Brian Urlacher play college football?", "answer": "University of New Mexico", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fede4566ce05a3942286ddc", "question": "In what country did Mia Hamm learn to play soccer?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aac7", "question": "Indianapolis is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "Indiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dd6", "question": "Who played the title character in the film \"The Omega Man\"?", "answer": "Charlton Heston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f9f4e82af848b908361b882", "question": "What year was Pinterest launched?", "answer": "2010", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f77", "question": "What was Gladys Knight's backing band?", "answer": "The Pips", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b570", "question": "What event led to the creation of the Superfund?", "answer": "The Three Mile Island incident", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca3", "question": "Oliver Mellors was the proper name of what D.H. Lawrence title character?", "answer": "Lady Chatterley's Lover", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6002436e4be4723ccac22196", "question": "In Jonathan Swift\u2019s \"Gulliver\u2019s Travels\", what is the name of the island inhabited by tiny people?", "answer": "Lilliput", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1e5", "question": "Who is Tippi Hedren's daughter?", "answer": "Melanie Griffith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a3b06c0f9723ab15cb50", "question": "Approximately, how many Americans served in World War II?", "answer": "16 million", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bb2", "question": "What band's 1993 debut album was entitled \"August and Everything After\"?", "answer": "Counting Crows", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133946e", "question": "Who played the role of Daisy Randone in the 1999 movie \"Girl, Interrupted\"?", "answer": "Brittany Murphy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fcc1c9ec97eb73f6a51a274", "question": "On what date did the Titanic sink?", "answer": "April 15, 1912", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c314", "question": "What irrational mathematical constant is known as the golden ratio?", "answer": "1.6180339887", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af8f", "question": "What civil rights activist was born Malcolm Little?", "answer": "Malcolm X", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd6629fa5bfecdd737e0846", "question": "Who were Virginia and West Virginia named for?", "answer": "Queen Elizabeth I, the Virgin Queen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b53b", "question": "Where is the sunniest place in the world?", "answer": "Yuma, Arizona", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c451", "question": "What element has the chemical symbol K?", "answer": "Potassium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b85", "question": "What\u2019s the ballet term for a 360 degree turn on one foot?", "answer": "A Pirouette", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ec2b29543630d44e5be228f", "question": "What is the traditional beverage of Churchill Downs and the Kentucky Derby?", "answer": "Mint Julep", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad14", "question": "In 1952, Albert Einstein was offered the presidency of what country?", "answer": "Israel", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b527", "question": "What are you supposed to do when presented with the wine cork from a freshly opened wine bottle?", "answer": "Look at it", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9dc", "question": "On which island will you find \"Adams Peak\"?", "answer": "Sri Lanka", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afc9", "question": "By what name is the Vieux Carre in New Orleans better known?", "answer": "French Quarter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b254", "question": "In what city did Rosa Parks refuse to move to the back of the bus?", "answer": "Montgomery, Alabama", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c89db4011619dd6d415488", "question": "In their school report, what did the boys in South Park claim to be present during the first Thanksgiving meal?", "answer": "Aliens", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ac", "question": "Julia Roberts and Hugh Grant were paired in what romantic comedy?", "answer": "Notting Hill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cc5", "question": "In what movie does Marlon Brando utter the infamous line \"Get the butter\"?", "answer": "Last Tango in Paris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b704", "question": "What was Charlie Chaplin's cane made of?", "answer": "Bamboo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ada", "question": "What sports team's jersey does Cameron wear in \"Ferris Bueller's Day Off\"?", "answer": "Detroit Red Wings", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b957", "question": "What golfer is nicknamed the \"Golden Bear\"?", "answer": "Jack Nicklaus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff1409fb0ee8c595b6d399e", "question": "Which famous artist wrote his notes in mirror script?", "answer": "Leonardo da Vinci", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b323700bf195a31e15d73c1", "question": "Which supermodel is nicknamed \"The Body\"?", "answer": "Elle Macpherson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4f6", "question": "What planet has a storm system called the \"Great Red Spot\"?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1fd", "question": "In what city did the First and Second Continental Congresses meet?", "answer": "Philadelphia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339410", "question": "What was the maiden name of \"Leave It to Beaver\" TV mom June Cleaver?", "answer": "Bronson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a69220565ad31a57c7db", "question": "What was the name of British General Charles Cornwallis' dogs?", "answer": "Mars and Jupiter", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7ca0e877e98cb97778a01", "question": "In which district of the United Kingdom is Scaffel Pike, England's highest peak, found?", "answer": "The Lake District", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b418", "question": "Julius Caesar and Napoleon were said to have suffered from what?", "answer": "Epilepsy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6002447a4be4723ccac221a4", "question": "How long did it take Leonardo da Vinci to paint the Mona Lisa's smile?", "answer": "Leonardo's greatest triumph was the smile of the Mona Lisa, which he labored on for 16 years up until his death.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339297", "question": "What is the name of the character Larry David plays in the TV show \"Curb Your Enthusiasm\"?", "answer": "Larry David", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e0c", "question": "What other late-night veteran succeeded Ed McMahon as the host of \"Star Search\" in a 2003 revival?", "answer": "Arsenio Hall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd38", "question": "In which nation did the woven-yarn craft of \"God's eyes\" originate?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c48", "question": "What year did fashion designer Alexander McQueen commit suicide?", "answer": "2010", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a513", "question": "In which sea is the island country of Malta?", "answer": "Mediterranean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133948c", "question": "In the movie \"Days of Thunder\", what car is Cole told to hit in his first race?", "answer": "The pace car", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392b3", "question": "What TV show premiered in 1974 and opened each week with an answering machine playing a different message?", "answer": "The Rockford Files", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339212", "question": "What rock star is credited as a co-writer and backing singer for David Bowie's \"Fame\"?", "answer": "John Lennon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ed4", "question": "What SNL cast member voiced \"Waldo\" in Van Halen's \"Hot for Teacher\" video?", "answer": "Phil Hartman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b4c", "question": "Who wrote the \"Man in the Iron Mask\"?", "answer": "Alexandre Dumas", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6018bbdcd96d05b23b281650", "question": "Who was the first Roman Catholic to be President of the United States?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a588", "question": "Which US state's name is derived from the Spanish words for \"mountainous\"?", "answer": "Montana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5990f4c4fa5fdd6dd25324e5", "question": "What country borders Central African Republic to the north?", "answer": "Chad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ef5", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Chingachgook?", "answer": "The Last of the Mohicans", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febb2ed7e83c707845b2115", "question": "\"Sonar\" stands for what?", "answer": "Sound Navigation And Ranging", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ef", "question": "Of the six main cast members on the TV show \u201cFriends\u201d, which was the oldest?", "answer": "Lisa Kudrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b46f", "question": "Which politician is known as Tarzan?", "answer": "Michael Heseltine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b81", "question": "Who played Jill Taylor on the TV show \"Home Improvement\"?", "answer": "Patricia Richardson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b220", "question": "What city was Billy Clanton killed in?", "answer": "Tombstone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339341", "question": "Who is Kyle's brother on the TV show \"South Park\"?", "answer": "Ike", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f20001dd7bf43be5e809", "question": "What is the word for the study of flags?", "answer": "Vexillology", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c1", "question": "What beer is known as the \"champagne of beers\"?", "answer": "Miller High Life", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ea9", "question": "What screen legend made his final appearance in the movie \"The Harder They Fall\"?", "answer": "Humphrey Bogart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ea7", "question": "What screen legend made his final appearance in the movie \"The Shootist\"?", "answer": "John Wayne", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338900", "question": "What metal is the \"The Statue of Liberty's\" visible surface constructed from?", "answer": "Copper", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60062a58c9d816e292245c17", "question": "What is Judy Chicago's most well-known work?", "answer": "Regarded as the first epic feminist artwork, \"The Dinner Party\" functions as a symbolic history of women in Western civilization.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cb7", "question": "Who wrote the 1971 novel \"The Exorcist\"?", "answer": "William Peter Blatty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339640", "question": "Oswald Cobblepot is better known as who?", "answer": "The Penguin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b65d", "question": "A \"beaver\" was an attachment to what piece of human armor?", "answer": "Helmet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594a62302ebb971c1417fb8d", "question": "Which French district does Claret come from?", "answer": "Bordeaux", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7b7", "question": "What two ingredients make a Black Velvet cocktail?", "answer": "Champagne and stout", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca6b", "question": "Who was the second man to walk on the Moon?", "answer": "Buzz Aldrin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6013709c1381754895396383", "question": "Actor Earl Hindman always hid behind a fence in which '90s TV show?", "answer": "\"Home Improvement\", which aired from 1991 to 1999.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e82", "question": "During what war was the novel \"The Hornet's Nest\" set?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c623", "question": "What is a nebula?", "answer": "A cloud of dust and gas", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0bf", "question": "What is the fear of progress known as?", "answer": "Prosophobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ed43e55d244b1771b64500e", "question": "In May 2020, which TV show broke the record for longest-running live-action comedy series when it was renewed for a 15th season?", "answer": "It's Always Sunny in Philadelphia", "category": "Entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389ef", "question": "What is the first name of Gianni Versace's sister who took control of the business after his death in 1997?", "answer": "Donatella", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe655e3ae7e414034b5aebd", "question": "What Greek figure was famously forced to complete 12 Labors?", "answer": "Hercules", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c415", "question": "What animal produces most of the world's wool?", "answer": "Sheep", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b4", "question": "When did sharpshooter Annie Oakley die?", "answer": "1926", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba582874c93a3298b2151", "question": "What name did George Costanza from the TV show \"Seinfeld\" want to name his first child?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd53", "question": "The Naismith Award is an award given in what field?", "answer": "College basketball", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcb6", "question": "What kind of fruit juice is used to mix a Cape Codder?", "answer": "Cranberry", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a542", "question": "What two US states begin with the letter \"T\"?", "answer": "Tennessee and Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff0b0bfe662d71a53650fcb", "question": "In Harry Potter's world, what is the first name of Andromeda Tonks daughter?", "answer": "Andromeda Tonks daughter and only child is Nymphadora Tonks.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec9", "question": "Kim Kardashian and Kanye West\u2019s second baby\u2019s name is what?", "answer": "Saint", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388b8", "question": "In the children's toe-counting rhyme, what did the third little piggy have?", "answer": "Roast Beef", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b644", "question": "What doll was patented by John Barton Gurelle in 1915?", "answer": "Raggedy Ann", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaab", "question": "Ankara is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d47470f8e329de4f87789c", "question": "Who was the Prime Minister of the UK throughout the 1980s?", "answer": "Marget Thatcher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae5d", "question": "What 1980\u2019s US president survived an assassination attempt?", "answer": "Ronald Regan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5904a4c7cf93664eb10486c6", "question": "Shortly after meeting David, which North American city did Katchoo disappear to for 2 months, in the comic series \"Strangers in Paradise\"?", "answer": "Toronto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7ec", "question": "Which continental South American country borders Panama?", "answer": "Colombia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b7ffb3b3a3a814d89068c63", "question": "Who is considered the Father of English literature?", "answer": "Geoffrey Chaucer", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b582", "question": "When was the Apple II computer introduced?", "answer": "1977", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c20c", "question": "Which country hosted the first Olympic Games after World War I?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bbc922560f0007efaba0e58", "question": "What is the capital of Morocco?", "answer": "Rabat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe93bce6bd93ce3a4e5f6a6", "question": "Percentage-wise, how big were the brains of the extinct species Australopithecus compared to a modern human brain?", "answer": "35%", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a04a", "question": "Gene, Louise, Tina, Bob, and Linda are the main characters of which animated sitcom?", "answer": "Bob's Burgers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a2", "question": "Which general's father led the investigation of the Lindbergh baby kidnapping?", "answer": "Norman Schwarzkopf", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eb8", "question": "What was the home US state of Alan Alda's characters in both \"M*A*S*H\" and \"The Aviator\"?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa4a56ce05a3942286eb6", "question": "What is the name of the cat in the film \"Hocus Pocus\"?", "answer": "Thackery Binx", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4d974f08b8581f80b092a9", "question": "What country was host to the \u201c2017 World Expo\u201d?", "answer": "Kazakhstan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a327", "question": "Who played the role of Jack Cates in the 1982 film \"48 Hrs.\"?", "answer": "Nick Nolte", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af98753aeb0982ee4559553", "question": "What is believed to be the first political cartoon published in colonial America?", "answer": "Join or Die Cartoon", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c732", "question": "What is the average gestation period of the African elephant?", "answer": "660 days", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2d4", "question": "What does a phonophobe fear?", "answer": "Noise", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a56c", "question": "Which US state is home to Cape Lookout National Seashore?", "answer": "North Carolina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d7a", "question": "The BBC once banned The Beatles' \"Come Together\" for \"advertising\" what product in the lyrics?", "answer": "Coca-Cola", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb1ff65ff7d326b622a6f", "question": "Petrology the study of what?", "answer": "Rocks", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c805", "question": "What kind of twins are also called \"dizygotic\"?", "answer": "Fraternal twins", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a2", "question": "Who is known as Eminem?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5bb", "question": "Which four US states share a border with Texas?", "answer": "Arkansas, Louisiana, New Mexico, Oklahoma", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b11d", "question": "In what year did Aaron Burr kill Alexander Hamilton in a duel?", "answer": "1804", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133964e", "question": "What kind of animal is the title character in the 1998 movie \"Mighty Joe Young\"?", "answer": "Gorilla", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca84", "question": "What French scientist is credited with inventing margarine?", "answer": "Hippolyte Mege-Mouries", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff3c1bc4f032c0db195b478", "question": "What tribe of Native Americans was the first to encounter the Pilgrims?", "answer": "The Wampanoag", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b03c", "question": "What was the name of the sect that was raided by the FBI in Waco, Texas in 1993?", "answer": "Branch Davidians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "592eaec8f83302ff91e4648c", "question": "Mark David Chapman became famous for what in 1980?", "answer": "Shooting John Lennon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a57b", "question": "US city Milwaukee is located on the shores of what lake?", "answer": "Lake Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cdc", "question": "What literary character's parents were murdered in Godric's Hollow?", "answer": "Harry Potter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389ee", "question": "What city provides the setting for \"The Phantom of the Opera\"?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c883", "question": "What popular computer language shares its name with the vitamin formerly known as ascorbic acid?", "answer": "C", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc4a", "question": "What item of clothing was Ralph Lauren's first product?", "answer": "A necktie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b3230fbbf195a31e15d7380", "question": "Which gland is enlarged in the condition known as \"goitre\"?", "answer": "The Thyroid gland", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c073", "question": "What is a \"Blenheim Orange\"?", "answer": "Apple", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bbd4bc600d154d7af00b8ce", "question": "Which nu metal band released the songs \"My Way\" and \"Rollin'\"?", "answer": "Limp Bizkit", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe733d3eec85e375820b225", "question": "What meeting of world powers near the end of World War II is often said to mark the beginning of the Cold War?", "answer": "The Yalta Conference", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a16d", "question": "Which Alan Parker film dealt with racial murders in America?", "answer": "Mississippi Burning", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af2a", "question": "The Bren light machine gun originated in which then country?", "answer": "Czechoslovakia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a162d06f01ec323f8491735", "question": "What do O.J Simpson's initials stand for?", "answer": "Orenthal James", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7b6", "question": "What is the capital of Belgium?", "answer": "Brussels", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3f6", "question": "What is the lowest land point on Earth?", "answer": "Dead Sea shore, Israel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5909d31dbb53d1af6588650f", "question": "What year did the TV special \"A Charlie Brown Christmas\" made its debut on CBS?", "answer": "1965", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7a8", "question": "What is the middle color in a rainbow?", "answer": "Green", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a620", "question": "What aquifer provides water for Nebraska, Kansas and Oklahoma?", "answer": "Ogallala aquifer", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe733a8eec85e375820b223", "question": "In a Nazi concentration camp, a black triangle identified a prisoner as what?", "answer": "Asocial", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339594", "question": "What type of wine does Miles refuse to drink in the movie \"Sideways\"?", "answer": "Merlot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59cdb00665ff7d326b622a5f", "question": "What country's entire population was condemned to death by the Spanish Inquisition?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b3232eebf195a31e15d7395", "question": "What movie marked Jodie Foster's directorial debut?", "answer": "Little Man Tate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339975", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Lenny's last name?", "answer": "Leonard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe9f6e7ff048f679a45aae0", "question": "The San Andreas Fault is an example of what type of tectonic plate boundary?", "answer": "Transform plate boundary", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4b7", "question": "What is the only nation that borders both Uruguay and Venezuela?", "answer": "Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "596dfd319616e6c6d4eba4f4", "question": "What is a baby swan called?", "answer": "A Cygnet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339717", "question": "Which 1995 movie stars Susan Sarandon and Sean Penn?", "answer": "Dead Man Walking", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b0c", "question": "What suit is the Queen is \"Alice's Adventures in Wonderland\"?", "answer": "Hearts", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8e4", "question": "What did Henry Shrapnel invent?", "answer": "Exploding shell", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febd3c97e83c707845b2155", "question": "Which electronic musical instrument emits the eeriest of sounds and is the only instrument played without touching it?", "answer": "Theremin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338feb", "question": "What kind of animal is Beatrix Potters' \"Mrs. Tiggy-Winkle\"?", "answer": "Hedgehog", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6010ca4c0775fa611bce67f6", "question": "What is another name for rubbing alcohol?", "answer": "Isopropyl alcohol -- It is a germicide that is effective against bacteria, viruses, and fungi.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338db0", "question": "Who are \"the night visitors\" in Gian Carlo Menotti's opera \"Amahl and the Night Visitors\"?", "answer": "Three wise men", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e6", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Bart of Darkness,\" what does Bart break?", "answer": "His leg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec22ac8dc25ca9e12ef629", "question": "Which French singer and actor sings the theme song to Disney's film \"The Aristocats\"?", "answer": "Maurice Chevalier", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd0a", "question": "What was the original brand of cereal pitched by Snap, Crackle and Pop?", "answer": "Rice Krispies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeb5", "question": "Which British dandy introduced long trousers as conventional wear for men?", "answer": "Beau Brummell", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b80", "question": "What 1991 movie featured the character Topper Harley?", "answer": "Hot Shots!", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf1e", "question": "What key is to the right of T on a standard keyboard?", "answer": "Y", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c848877e98cb977789e1", "question": "Which country has hosted the Wife Carrying World Championships since the competition\u2019s founding in 1992?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399c5", "question": "What was Mr. Seaver's first name on the TV show \"Growing Pains\"?", "answer": "Jason", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b393", "question": "Who was the 35th President of the US?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c79", "question": "What animal is Indiana Jones afraid of?", "answer": "Snakes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7ca49877e98cb97778a05", "question": "Which Asian capital was formerly known as Batavia?", "answer": "Jakarta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c976", "question": "What does an ombrometer measure?", "answer": "Rainfall", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd66bcea5bfecdd737e0889", "question": "Which espresso drink is named for a religious order?", "answer": "Cappuccino", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef94406ce05a3942286e95", "question": "Where was the game Chinese Checkers originally produced?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb4997e83c707845b211a", "question": "What color is eigengrau?", "answer": "Dark gray", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6b4", "question": "What type of bird is the Brown Thrasher?", "answer": "Songbird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffb5ed75dad637d903c8826", "question": "What World Heritage Site's name translates to \"holy wisdom\"?", "answer": "Hagia Sophia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8b8", "question": "In what city would you find Boboli Gardens?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59049ececf93664eb10486b6", "question": "Dogteeth tetras are a family of freshwater fishes native to what continent?", "answer": "South America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5971debf89261e916c8e09a3", "question": "The beaver is the national emblem of which country?", "answer": "Canada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b36f", "question": "James Hunt was disqualified after winning which Grand Prix?", "answer": "1976 British Grand Prix", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0d1", "question": "Billed as \"The Crime of the Century\", in which US city did the Great Brink's Robbery take place, in 1950?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4c5049076251badbead1", "question": "The term \"first family\" came into popularity under which U.S. President?", "answer": "John F. Kennedy -- Comedian/Kennedy impressionist Vaughn Meader titled his Grammy-winning 1962 album \"First Family\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5909cc60bb53d1af658864e0", "question": "On which three days of the week is December 25th more likely to fall?", "answer": "Tuesday, Friday or Sunday", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b64b", "question": "In cakes, what is the difference between icing and frosting?", "answer": "There is no difference", "category": "general"}]